

MATTHEW CALLAHAN

Software Engineer | Phoenix, Arizona

EDUCATION



University of Wisconsin-MadisonB.S., Geographic Information Systems

EXPERIENCE

Republic Services | Scottsdale, AZ | December 2018 - Present Staff Engineer (May 2019 - Present)

- Lead a team of eight developers and testers, overseeing talent development, skill set improvement, and acting as a mentor to all team members.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development (.NET 5 back end & Angular 11 front end).
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage on all apps, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and currently leading effort to refactor all applications to follow these guidelines.

Senior Developer (December 2018 - May 2019)

- Developed enterprise GIS web applications which provided data mapping and route visualization tools to assist in business operations (.NET, Angular, ArcGIS).
- Developed APIs and services to deliver spatial data to teams and applications throughout the company (ASP.NET Web API).
- Supported desktop application development for GIS data analysis and batch data processing (ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Implemented a uniform Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories.

Carvana | Tempe, AZ | February 2018 – December 2018 Software Engineer

- Primary job function was back end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com using C#, .NET & .NET Core.
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for vehicle inventory search engine (JS ES6+, React/Redux, AngularJS).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

CBRE | Tempe, AZ | March 2008 - February 2018

Application Developer (January 2011 – February 2018)

- Developed web applications which provided mapping and site selection data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients using ASP.NET MVC.
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data processing and analysis using C# .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python.
- Administered on-prem servers (Windows Server, IIS, SQL Server, ArcGIS Server).

GIS Technician (March 2008 – January 2011)

- Developed scripts and desktop GIS tools to automate tasks.
- Created custom maps, and market research reports for brokerage staff, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.

ABOUT ME

My name is Matthew Callahan. I am a software engineer and a team leader. I have over ten years of experience in web and desktop software development. Learning the continually changing landscape of computer programming is my passion.

CONTACT

Email: matthew.callahan@outlook.com

Phone: 630-988-1555

Homepage: mfcallahan.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GitHub: github.com/mfcallahan

Blog: seesharpdotnet.wordpress.com

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

KEY SKILLS

Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

Frameworks

.NET & .NET Core, Angular, React, Node.js, ArcGIS

Testing

NUnit, Jasmine, Mocha, Selenium, Cypress

Dev Tools

Azure, Git, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Splunk, SQL Server